Guide to the John N. Paden papers, 1938-2010
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
- Series 2: Research, 1950s-2007; (81 boxes)
  - Bibliographies, Winter 1967-Winter 1969 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Bibliography-Abuja, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Bibliography-African Creative Writing, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Bibliography-Modern African religious movements, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Bibliography-Traditional and Modern Africa, March 1968 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Black Africa, 1970s (Box 21, Folder 3)
    Research for Dr. Paden's book of the same title
  - Black Africa, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Folder 1 of 2. Research for Dr. Paden's book of the same title.
  - Black Africa, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
    Folder 2 of 2. Research for Dr. Paden's book of the same title.
  - Black Africa II-Revisions, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Work for Dr. Paden's book of the same title.
  - Black Africa: A Handbook for Comparative Analysis, 1960s-1970s (Box 21, Folder 7)
    Folder 1 of 3. Work for Dr. Paden's book of the same title.
  - Black Africa: A Handbook for Comparative Analysis, 1960s-1970s (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Folder 2 of 3. Work for Dr. Paden's book of the same title.
  - Black Africa: A Handbook for Comparative Analysis, 1960s-1970s (Box 22, Folder 2)
    Folder 3 of 3. Work for Dr. Paden's book of the same title.
  - Black Africa-Drafts, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Black student crisis at Northwestern, April-May, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Black student crisis at Northwestern, April-May, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Black student crisis at Northwestern, April-May, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Book dust jackets, 1960s (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Book dust jackets, 1960s (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Books to order, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Bori-Peace Corps lecture, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Boston University Conference, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Includes related correspondence, Dr. Paden's notes, programs, and papers.
  - Brotherhood, 1960s (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Relationships between sects.
  - Business cards, various, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - CDR working papers, November 1977 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - CSIS, 1990s (Box 23, Folder 9)
    Nigeria working group notes and meetings.
  - CSIS and CCA policy conference, March 11, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Center for International Affairs, Harvard, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Chapter: Scope and Content, 1960s (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Chapter 3 A Short History of Regionalism in East Africa, undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Chapter IV, 2, Mahdi, 1960s (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Chapter 4, revised, 1960s (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Chapter V.5. "Ideational cohes.", 1960s (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Chapter V.6. "Structural integ.-relational process", 1960s (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Chapter "7.5 Case study of Niger-Nigerian relations (draft)", undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Chapter 14, 1960s (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Chapters, miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 24, Folder 7)
    Folder 1 of 5.
  - Chapters, miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 24, Folder 8)
    Folder 2 of 5.
  - Chapters, miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 24, Folder 9)
    Folder 3 of 5.
  - Chapters, miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 24, Folder 10)
    Folder 4 of 5.
  - Chapters, miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Folder 5 of 5.
  - Charts, 1960s (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Chicago Council on Foreign Relations, January 20, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Chicago Tribune: articles/replies on Africa, September 1981 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Childbirth and other medical, 1960s (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Children, 1960s (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Classroom materials, Ahmadu Bello, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Classroom materials, GMU, INTL 501: Career Information, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    Research and course notes.
  - Classroom materials, GMU, INTL 501: Conflict Resolution, March 8, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Classroom materials, GMU, INTL 501: Corporate Culture, 1992, 1995, February 1998 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Classroom materials, GMU, INTL 501: Culture and International Transactions, 1995, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Classroom materials, GMU, INTL 501: Europe, March 1995 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Classroom materials, GMU, INTL 501: Europe, March 1998 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Classroom materials, GMU, INTL 501: Global Negotiator, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Classroom materials, GMU, INTL 501: Japan, April 1995 -1998 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Classroom materials, GMU, INTL 501: Kinship and family values, 1997-1998 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Classroom materials, GMU, INTL 501: Muslim World, 1996-1999 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Classroom materials, GMU, INTL 501: Russia, 1996, 1997, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Classroom materials, GMU, INTL 501: Time, February 12, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Classroom materials, GMU, INTL 501: various, 1995-1999 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Classroom materials, GMU, INTL 605: various, Spring 1999 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Classroom materials, GMU, INTL 720/MAIT 720 with Dr. Atsuko Abe, July 1997 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Classroom materials, GMU, ITRN 605, Spring 1999 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Classroom materials, GMU, ITRN 605: Culture, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Classroom materials, Northwestern, A-01, 1977-1978 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Classroom materials, Northwestern, A-10, 1970s (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Classroom materials, Northwestern, A-10, 1970s (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Classroom materials, Northwestern, A-10, 1970s (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Classroom materials, Northwestern, A-10, 1977-1978 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    Folder 1 of 2. Research and course notes.
  - Classroom materials, Northwestern, A-10, 1977-1978 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    Folder 2 of 2. Research and course notes.
  - Classroom materials, Northwestern, C-44, Fall 1977 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Classroom materials, Northwestern, C-44, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Classroom materials, Northwestern, C-95, 1976-1977 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Classroom materials, Northwestern, C-95, Winter 1978 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Classroom materials, Northwestern, D-58, 1976-1977 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Classroom materials, Northwestern, E-40, October 10, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Classroom materials, Northwestern, E-40: China, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Classroom materials, various, 1966-1969 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Classroom materials, various, 1966-1969 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1960s-1970s (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Cohen, Ronald, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    Kano related research, Ahmadu Bello University priorities.
  - Colloquium on Black Civilization and Education, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Contact information, various, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Contemporary African Arts proposal, October 1, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Corporate Council on Africa, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Crowder, Michael, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    "'Us' and 'Them': The International African Institute and the Current Crisis of Identity in African Studies."
  - Curriculum vita, March 1980 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Data Bank, 1970s (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Datebook, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    Personal record book
  - Dalton, George., July 1968 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    Title IX: Foreign Assistance Act. Folder 1 of 2.
  - Dalton, George., July 1968 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    Title IX: Foreign Assistance Act. Folder 2 of 2.
  - Dantiye, Nasiru Ibrahim, June 1973 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    Tuareg and Buzu Immigration into Kano
  - Declaration of Trust Creating the Aminu Kano Studies Center Association Trust, January 29-April 16, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Definitions, Nation Building, September 1, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Development, Administration. Post-War, 1969, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Development, World Bank reprints, 1978-1979 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Dissertation, marked early draft, undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Dissertation, marked early draft, undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Dissertation, marked early draft, June 1966 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Division of Nigerian States-language and culture, 1960s (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Draft, long outline, Ann Paden, 1960s (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Drinking Ink, 1960s (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Drought and Environmental Management in West Africa, 1974-1975 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Drought in Africa, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    Papers from presentations.
  - Drought in Africa, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Drought in Africa, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Eastern Region, Provincial Administration Edict, 1966 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Economic History Seminar, January 5-10, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    Folder 1 of 3. Papers from presentations.
  - Economic History Seminar, January 5-10, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    Folder 2 of 3. Papers from presentations.
  - Economic History Seminar, January 5-10, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    Folder 3 of 3. Papers from presentations.
  - Economics, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Education, 1960s (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Education, 1960s (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Education, 1965, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Education, 1963 Directory of Primary Schools (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Education, 1970s (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Education, October 1972 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    Selected Syllabi for Introductory, Interdisciplinary Courses on Africa.
  - Education, Paden's, 1959-1963 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Experimental College: Nigeria/Biafra, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - External familial relations, 1960s (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Falke collection, undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
    Code sheets 501-600.
  - Falke, computer project, 1973-1974 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Falke, Umar(e), manuscripts, 1970s (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Falke, Umar(e), manuscripts, 1970s (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Figures and illustrations, 1960s (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Folk tales of the West Lake, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Food, Ann Paden, 1960s (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Ford Foundation, October 1972 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Ford Foundation, February-March 1978 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Ford Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Foreign and Foreign language education, 1980s (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Free Press, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Fulani background information and sources, 1920s-1960s (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Fulani bibliography, April 1974 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Fulani bibliography, undated (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Fulani and jihad, undated (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - GMU-Master of Arts in International Transactions, 1998 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Gara technology, dyeing, November 1977 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - General strike, 1964 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Georgia, Ann Paden, 1960s (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Germany, 1986 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Ghana, 1960s (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Ghana, 1990s (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Ghana clippings, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Government of African Cities conference, April 18-19, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Grants and fellowships, 1963 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Handmade book, undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Harvard notes, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 5)
    Dr. Paden's student work.
  - Harvard notes, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Harvard notes, bibliography, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Harvard notes, expatriate firms, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Harvard notes, foreign cultures, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Harvard notes, imperialism, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Harvard notes, special topics, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Harvard notes, traditional politics, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Harvard Strike, March 1-April 24, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Harvard Strike, April 11, 1969-January 15, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Hausa, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Hausa, 1970s-1980s (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Hausa-An Introduction, 1965 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Hausa, Arabic, English, undated (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Hausa background information and sources, 1907-1959 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    Includes information on language and folklore.
  - Hausa background information and sources, 1960s (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Hausa background information and sources, undated (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Hausa cultural program, undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Hausa culture, various, Ann Paden, 1960s (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Hausa final report: Appendix, July-August 1982 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Hausa folk-tales, sources, 1885-1913 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Hausa, Gealy, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Hausa, Introductory Workbook, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Hausa language, January 1964 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    Includes handwritten notes.
  - Hausa language, undated (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Hausa language, undated (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Hausa language, undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Hausa language, undated (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Hausa language, undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Hausa language, undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Hausa language, undated (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Hausa language, background information and sources, 1920s-1960s (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Hausa language publications, 1950s-1960s (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Hausa linguistics, 1950s-1960s (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Hausa literature, 1959-1960s (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Hausa literature, poetry, and literacy, 1940s-1960s (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Hausa poetry and music, 1957-1968 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Hausa religious poetry in Ajani Script, manuscript, August 1969 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Hausa religious poetry in Ajani Script, manuscript, August 1969 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Hausa religious poetry in Ajani Script, manuscript, August 1969 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Hausa religious poetry in Ajani Script, manuscript, August 1969 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Hausa Studies, cultural, 1904-1915 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    Reprinted articles for research done in the 1960s.
  - Hausa Studies, cultural, 1936-1964 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Hausa Studies, cultural, 1965-1968 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Hausa summer language institute, 1981-1982 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Hausa summer language institute, 1981-1982 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Hausa summer language institute, 1981-1982 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Hausa summer language institute, 1982 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Hausa summer language institute, undated (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Hausa summer language institute - people, 1982 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Heineke, Patrick, March 1984 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Herbs, analyses, 1960s (Box 41, Folder 5)
    Uses in planting, medicinally, and in folklore.
  - Historical Society of Nigeria Conference, January 1-4, 1969 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Historical Society of Nigeria Conference, December 18-21, 1974 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - History and Culture seminar, June 28-August 10, 1985 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Holm, John, undated (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Hopkins, A. G. (Antonio), 1980 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Housing the Urban Poor Seminar, 1979-1980 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    At Northwestern University.
  - Human Rights, undated (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Hunwick, J. O., 1964 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    A New Source for the Biography of Ahmad Baba Al-Tinbukti.
  - I.A.I, June 1985 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    Material relating to African Studies and associated meetings.
  - I.A.I, July 1986 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - I.A.I, September 1987 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - I.A.I. Executive Council, 1983-1984 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - I.A.I. Executive Council, July 19-20 1986 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - I.A.I. Executive Council, 1987 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - ICPR, 1st. Edition, 1971 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Ibrahim, Daudu Umar, June 1964 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Images of Nigeria, greeting cards and postcards, 1960s-1970s (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Indiana Conference, May 1971 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Infant Mortality, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Instability and National Integration, 1970s (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Instability and National Integration, 1970s (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Inter-Regional Meeting on Development, 1983 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - International Academic Union, 1982-1983 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - International Academic Union, 1984-1985 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - International Education, 1980s (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - International Relations, 1963-1964 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - International Seminar on the Economic Status of Muslim Minorities, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - International, various, May 9, 1996-October 13, 1998 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Interview: Garba X Saidu, Kano, July 24, 1965 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Introduction-draft, undated (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Islam, African ethnic groups, sources, 1950s-1960s (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Islam, Ahmadiyya, 1924-1964 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Islam, Arabic sources of African History, 1960s (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Islam background information and sources, 1902-1959 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Islam background information and sources, 1960-1964 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Islam background information and sources, 1965-1967 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Islam background information and sources, 1979-undated (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Islam, general, 1960s (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Islam, Ghana, 1960s (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Islam, Guinea, 1960s (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Islam, Jihad theory, 1950 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Islam, legal and Islamic law, Africa, 1950s-1960s (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Islam, Mauretan, 1949-1951 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Islam, Mouridiyya, 1962-1966 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Islam Nigeria, Education, background information and sources, 1938-1961 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Islam Nigeria, Legal, background information and sources, 1916-1961 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Islam Nigeria, Newspapers and propaganda, April 1965 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Islam, Northern Nigeria, January-June 1965 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Islam, Qadiriyya, 1951-1965 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Islam, Sanusiyya, 1924-1967 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Islam, Senegal, 1960s (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Islam, Tijaniyya, 1924-1966 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Islam, Various, 1960s (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Islam, West Africa, 1960s (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Islam, West Africa, 1962-1966 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Islam, West Africa, undated (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Islam, Women, 1964-1966 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Islamic Conference, June 1981 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Islamic Congress, Jos, 1956 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Islamic pamphlets, 1934-1994 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Islamic Revival Conference, May 28-31, 1980 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Islamic Studies, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Ivory Coast, 1960s (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Izah, Paul, 1977-1980 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Journal, African trip, 1960s (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Personal record book and notes.
  - KGSM, International Business in Nigeria, June 1981 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - KGSM, International Business in Nigeria, June 1981 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Kano, 1970s (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Kano, Aminu, biography, 1965 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Kano: "Additions to Part I/Part II", 1958-1965 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Kano, Aminu. Girls' education, undated (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Kano "Arabs", 1943, 1955 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Kano background information and sources, 1907-1909 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    Notes, reprints of scholarly work, journal articles for research done in the 1960s.
  - Kano background information and sources, 1910-1938 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Kano background information and sources, 1951-1959 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Kano background information and sources, 1963-1966 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    Notes, reprints of scholarly work, journal articles.
  - Kano background information and sources, 1967-1968 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Kano background information and sources, undated (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Kano City-State civil war, undated (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Kano district notebooks, undated (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Kano district heads by merit, undated (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Kano, economics and urbanization, 1960s (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Kano, education and youth, 1960s (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Kano expedition, 1903 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    Reprint for research done in the 1960s.
  - Kano geography and demography, 1950s-1960s (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Kano dissertation research, 1960s (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Kano dissertation various, 1960s (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Kano City (URBAN) Report, 1921 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Kano government, 1981 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Kano land and culture, 1938-March 1965 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Kano miscellaneous notes and sources, 1950s-1960s (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Kano miscellaneous notes and sources, 1970 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Kano miscellaneous notes and sources, undated (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Kano pre-colonial, notes, 1960s (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Kano religion, 1950s-1960s (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Kano "State Mod Agent-K.P.P.", 1965 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Kano, various, 1907-1950s (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Kano, various, 1952-1965 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Kano, various, 1952-December 23, 1966 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Kano, various, 1960s (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Kano, various, 1960s (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Kano, various, 1960s-1970s (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Kano, various, 1965 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Kano, various, 1970s (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Kano, various, undated (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Kanuri culture, background information and sources, 1930s-1950s (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Kanuri culture, background information and sources, 1960s (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Katsina Emir MSS, undated (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Kinship and marriage, Ann Paden, 1960s (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Kirk-Greene, 1966, 1967, September 1986 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    Vocabulary of Schoolboy Slang in N. Nigeria, Qualification of Office, Review of Bello Book.
  - Kubanni Dam Research Project Draft, undated (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Land issues, 1960s (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Language and region, 1960s-1970s (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Language, greetings, names, Ann Paden, 1960s (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Lectures on Nigeria, 1994, 1996 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Liberia segment of History and Culture Seminar, June 28-August 10, 1985 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Linguistic inventory of West Africa, 1953 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Local color writing, 1960s (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Manpower and unemployment research in Africa, 1969-1970 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Maternity report for two years, April 1, 1959-March 31, 1961 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Medical reports, Ann Paden, 1960s (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Medical reports, Ann Paden, 1960s (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Medicinal plants, undated (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Methodology, 1964-1965 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Minnesota lecture, 1979 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous data marked "irrelevant", 1960s (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous ethnic notes, 1960s-1970s (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous ethnic notes, undated (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Mit Sahel Sudano, 1970s (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Modern political authority, 1964-1964 (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Modern political community, August 1964 (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Modern politics, 1960s (Box 54, Folder 1)
    Sources and early field notes.
  - Modern politics, 1965 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Musa, Alhaji Abdulkadir Balarabe, November 10, 1980 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    Factors Responsible for the Conflict between the Executive and Legislature in Kaduna State.
  - Niger Delta, 2008-2009 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - N.P.C., July 13, 1963-December 19, 1964 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - NUP African Experience, undated (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Nation-specific politics and elections, 1970s-1980s (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - National Endowment for Democracy, 1995, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities grant, 1987 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Niass, Ibrahim trial, 1960s (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Nigeria, drug war, May-June 1995 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Nigeria educational, 1960s (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Nigeria election results, 1998 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Nigeria Federal election, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Nigeria-Federalism, December 8-10, 1998 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Nigeria GMU, April 28, 1999 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Nigeria Institute for Contemporary Research, 1999 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Nigeria Military, March 1999 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Nigeria news clippings, 1995 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Nigeria news clippings, 1995 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Nigeria news clippings, 1996 (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - Nigeria, northern schools, 1960s (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Nigeria notes, 1995 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Nigeria notes, undated (Box 56, Folder 3)